<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>dental imaging software</title>
    <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DentalImagingSoftware/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DentalImagingSoftware" />
    <updated>2022-06-22T21:58:04-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Dentist</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DentalImagingSoftware</id>

    <entry>
        <title>What is Dental Imaging?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dentist</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DentalImagingSoftware/what-is-dental-imaging.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DentalImagingSoftware/what-is-dental-imaging.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-22T21:58:04-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    What is Dental Imaging? Care providers can't get an accurate picture of the patient's oral health without performing an oral exam. Dr. Dentists need to be able see any troubling conditions, including hidden decay or extra teeth. They also have to know if the patient&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>What is Dental Imaging?</h2>
<p>Care providers can't get an accurate picture of the patient's oral health without performing an oral exam. Dr. Dentists need to be able see any troubling conditions, including hidden decay or extra teeth. They also have to know if the patient is experiencing bone loss due gum disease.</p>
<p>That's where imaging technology comes in. It allows professionals to get more clear and comprehensive pictures of teeth, tissue, nerves and bone inside the mouth. These images can then be studied, stored and compared over time to track improvements or identify worsening conditions.</p>
<p>DentiMax Software displaying an X-ray image</p>
<p>Because dentists can detect problems early, dental imaging helps them to make more precise diagnoses. They can also share images with patients and point out specific problems. This allows them to educate their patients better.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://media.dentalcompare.com/m/25/images/mediadent-imaging-digital-x-ray-software-10232-400x300.jpg?ts=637899648378322244" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" data-cke-saved-src=" https://media.dentalcompare.com/m/25/images/mediadent-imaging-digital-x-ray-software-10232-400x300.jpg?ts=637899648378322244"></p>
<h2>Dentimax</h2>
<p>Curve Dental</p>
<p>DentiMax</p>
<p>Curve Dental</p>
<p>DentiMax</p>
<p>Good imaging software can make a big difference when it comes to a dental practice's profitability. Since most dentists need to see a certain number of patients per day to cover costs, it's important for their workflow to be as efficient as possible. Unfortunately, clunky or outdated imaging software is often a barrier to achieving peak productivity, because it requires you to spend more time figuring out the system's kinks than analyzing your patient's images.</p>
<p>Whether you're looking to replace an existing dental imaging solution, or you're seeking software for a new practice, we're here to help you make a smart purchase decision to keep operations running smoothly. These tips are applicable to all types of practices, regardless of size or specialty.</p>
<ul>
<li>General dentists</li>
<li>Pediatric dentists</li>
<li>Prosthodontists</li>
<li>Orthodontists</li>
<li>Periodontologists</li>
<li>Endodontist</li>
<li>Implantologists</li>
<li>Maxillofacial and oral surgeons</li>
</ul>
<p>We'll give you a brief definition of dental imaging before explaining the software deployment options available to you, common technical features to compare systems by and screenshots to illustrate functionalities.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Digital Dental Imaging Software Explained</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dentist</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DentalImagingSoftware/digital-dental-imaging-software-explained.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DentalImagingSoftware/digital-dental-imaging-software-explained.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-22T21:57:36-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Digital Dental Imaging Software Explained In the past, dentists' offices had film-based radiography equipment that required a darkroom to process images. With the dawn of digital dental imaging tools (and their accompanying software systems), many providers have realized the old method is a time-consuming and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/603d402a7f5044d63413b245/60a27f075a13ec1d32d0c3ad_Group%201.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" data-cke-saved-src=" https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/603d402a7f5044d63413b245/60a27f075a13ec1d32d0c3ad_Group%201.png"></h2>
<h2>Digital Dental Imaging Software Explained</h2>
<p>In the past, dentists' offices had film-based radiography equipment that required a darkroom to process images. With the dawn of digital dental imaging tools (and their accompanying software systems), many providers have realized the old method is a time-consuming and ineffective way to use practice resources.</p>
<p>Digital imaging practices don't require a darkroom. They can use sensors, pans or intraoral cameras instead. There's no need for chemical processing, as the images from these devices are immediately generated and accessible via computer.</p>
<p>Here are some of the advantages of digital imaging as described by a study published in the Journal of the American Dental Association (JADA):</p>
<ul>
<li>Immediate image production</li>
<li>Display on interactive monitor with ability to magnify image details and take direct measurements</li>
<li>Perfect radiographic duplicates for referral purposes</li>
<li>Security mechanisms to identify original images and differentiate them from altered images</li>
<li>The ability to tag information such as a patient identifier, date of exposure and other relevant details</li>
</ul>
<p>These benefits are being embraced by many practices. In a Software Advice report of dental software buyer trends, we discovered the greatest amount of dental professionals (18 percent) specifically cite imaging device and/or digital sensor integration as their top-requested software functionality.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dental Imaging Software</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dentist</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DentalImagingSoftware/dental-imaging-software.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DentalImagingSoftware/dental-imaging-software.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-22T21:56:02-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Dental Imaging Software Industry Standard Imaging XrayVision incorporates the latest advancements in imaging technology and Apteryx's patented STB (Secure Tagged Block) file format, an unmodifiable, secure and "loss-less" imaging format. XrayVision also exports to a number of common image file formats, including TIFF, JPEG, and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1>Dental Imaging Software</h1>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://dentimax.com/wp-content/themes/betheme-child-2/assets/img/dental_imaging_software_image_comparison.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Industry Standard Imaging</h2>
<p>XrayVision incorporates the latest advancements in imaging technology and Apteryx's patented STB (Secure Tagged Block) file format, an unmodifiable, secure and "loss-less" imaging format. XrayVision also exports to a number of common image file formats, including TIFF, JPEG, and BMP for universal viewing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Compatible with a wide variety of hardware including the majority of manufactured intra-oral sensors, phosphor plate scanners, panoramic and cephalometric units, intra-oral cameras, extra-oral cameras, 3D tomography, CT scan, and flat bed scanners.</li>
</ul>
<p>It is compatible with many hardware, including most manufactured intra-oral scanners, phosphor plates scanners, panoramic or cephalometric units and intra-oral cameras.</p>
<ul>
<li>Contains a large variety of image analysis tools and enhancements that will allow the user to accurately diagnose and improve on the image quality.</li>
</ul>
<p>It contains a variety of enhancements and image analysis tools that allow users to diagnose the problem and then improve the quality.</p>
<ul>
<li>XrayVision enables users to capture images into completely customizable mounts</li>
</ul>
<p>XrayVision enables users to capture images into completely customizable mounts</p>
<ul>
<li>XrayVision is capable of importing images, exporting, burning to cd, and can integrate with your outlook email account to send images.</li>
</ul>
<p>XrayVision is capable of importing images, exporting, burning to cd, and can integrate with your outlook email account to send images.</p>
<h2>Dentimax</h2>
<p>Curve Dental</p>
<p>DentiMax</p>
<p>Curve Dental</p>
<p>DentiMax</p>
<p>A good imaging program can help improve a practice's financial health. It is important that dentists see as many patients as they can each day in order to make a profit. Older or clunky imaging software can often be a hindrance to your ability to achieve peak productivity. This is because you have to spend more time trying to figure out how the system works than actually analyzing patient images.</p>
<p>We can help you choose the right software to fit your needs. These tips are applicable to all types of practices, regardless of size or specialty.</p>
<ul>
<li>General dentists</li>
<li>Pediatric dentists</li>
<li>Prosthodontists</li>
<li>Orthodontists</li>
<li>Periodontologists</li>
<li>Endodontists</li>
<li>Implantologists</li>
<li>Oral and maxillofacial surgeons</li>
</ul>
<p>We'll give you a brief definition of dental imaging before explaining the software deployment options available to you, common technical features to compare systems by and screenshots to illustrate functionalities.</p>
<p>To read more, click on the section you like:</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.dmiequipment.ie/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/DIS_All_images_LoRes.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>What is Dental Imaging?</h2>
<p>Care providers can't get an accurate picture of the patient's oral health without performing an oral exam. Dentists must be able to see if there are any worrisome conditions that are obstructed from their view, such as hidden tooth decay, impacted/extra teeth, bone loss from gum disease and/or the growth of any abscesses, cysts or tumors.</p>
<p>Imaging technology is the solution. This technology allows professional to take clearer and more detailed pictures of the teeth, tissues, nerves, and bones inside the mouth. These images can then be studied, stored and compared over time to track improvements or identify worsening conditions.</p>
<p>An X-ray image viewed on DentiMax software</p>
<p>Dental imaging is necessary because it gives dentists a better chance of detecting problem areas early for more accurate diagnoses. It also allows them to better educate patients because they can share the images, point to specific areas of concern and show why it's important to adhere to treatment recommendations.</p>
<h2>Digital Dental Imaging Explained</h2>
<p>In the past, dentists' offices had film-based radiography equipment that required a darkroom to process images. With the dawn of digital dental imaging tools (and their accompanying software systems), many providers have realized the old method is a time-consuming and ineffective way to use practice resources.</p>
<p>Digital imaging practices don't require a darkroom. They can use sensors, pans or intraoral cameras instead. These images can be generated instantly and accessed via the computer without any chemical processing.</p>
<p>Here are some of the advantages of digital imaging as described by a study published in the Journal of the American Dental Association (JADA):</p>
<ul>
<li>Instant image production</li>
<li>Interactive monitor display with the ability to enhance image features and make direct measurements</li>
<li>Perfect radiographic duplicates for referral purposes</li>
<li>Security mechanisms to identify original images and differentiate them from altered images</li>
<li>Ability to tag data such as patient identification, date of exposure or other pertinent details</li>
</ul>
<p>These benefits are being embraced by many practices. In a Software Advice report of dental software buyer trends, we discovered the greatest amount of dental professionals (18 percent) specifically cite imaging device and/or digital sensor integration as their top-requested software functionality.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.midmark.com/images/default-source/products/dental/imaging/imaging-software/progeny-imaging/progeny-imaging.jpg?sfvrsn=71223845_2" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>What'S So Great About Rounded Corners?</h2>
<p>Every digital sensor design has to balance between field of view and patient comfort. Increasing the field of view can be achieved by increasing the size of the sensor. A larger sensor can produce more diagnostic information but it is more difficult for patients to use.</p>
<p>Round corners maximize this compromise by decreasing the patient pinch where it hurts, while still improving the field of vision. Sensors with only one or two rounded corners are less comfortable than sensors with four corners.</p>
<p>Have a look at the Eva Select Dental Sensor System</p>
<h2>Power Function</h2>
<ul>
<li>Single Click Capture from specific devices</li>
<li>Customizable Layouts/Mounts for Bitewings, FMX, etc.</li>
<li>You can select multiple images to compare/review</li>
<li>Easy and powerful annotation tools</li>
<li>Measuring tool for manual or auto calibration</li>
<li>Extremely easy to adjust brightness, contrast and gamma</li>
<li>The Customizable image Contrast Enhancement function (ICE) allows you to adjust filters that enhance images in various ways.</li>
<li>Powerful Device Image Quality (IQ) default settings</li>
<li>Import/Export of images</li>
</ul>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://orthodonticproductsonline.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/CarestreamDental_CS-Airway-1280x640.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Expertise To Help You Optimize For Your Needs</h2>
<p>Our company has been doing dental imaging for over three decades (our company used to be Dent-x), and we have helped thousands of dental offices make the most of their imaging systems. We've seen it all, and whether your questions are technical or clinical, you have a deep team of experts at your fingertips.</p>
<p>Read Article: The Seven Most Common Questions When Implementing a New Dental Intraoral Sensor System</p>
<ul>
<li>Enormous new diagnostic information unlocked and at your fingertips</li>
</ul>
<h2>Tigerview Dental Software: Important Benefits</h2>
<p>TigerView's Dental intuitive user interface makes it easy for offices to get up and running in no time.</p>
<p>TigerView integrates with almost every Dental Practice Management System. Some with Direct Integration and some with a one click bridge.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.pinimg.com/originals/19/98/f1/1998f1b89ebd6cc26765a450f3762e28.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Small Animal Specific Panoramic Dental Image Processing Technology</h2>
<p>MyVet Pan i2D uses tomography to take a panoramic image of small animal's full mouth within a minute. A switch to select the size of an animal and a laser light that guides them in positioning their patient correctly and quickly. Practioners will enjoy a more comfortable workflow with the ergonomically designed table. This allows for easy positioning and requires less preparation. The entire unit is mobile and unlike other medical system, a practioner can use it instantly without any special installation.</p>
<h2>Dental Imaging Solutions For Dentists</h2>
<p>Dental offices require software efficiency and seamless integration when it comes to the management of digital images. TigerView is the best and most user-friendly solution to view and capture images in your dental office.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/603d402a7f5044d63413b245/60a27f075a13ec1d32d0c3ad_Group%201.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Apteryx Imaging Software</h2>
<p>Use a single dental imaging software package to simplify your practice's workflow. Apteryx offers state-of the-art open architecture digital imaging software that can be used with intraoral and extraoral scanners, as well as digital X-ray sensors.</p>
<p>XrayVision software and XVlite software can capture, enhance, and display your entire dental image collection. XrayVision, XVlite and other practice management software can be automatically pulled into Apteryx to pull in patient data.</p>
<h2>Tigerview Imaging Software</h2>
<p>Among the best in its class, TigerView works with almost any dental X-ray equipment. This powerful, easy-to-use image management software lets you store all patient images in the computer for easy access from your practice management system.</p>
<p>TigerView can capture and store all types of dental images, including digital X-rays, film X-rays, intraoral camera images and digital camera shots. Images can be accessed easily once they are stored in TigerView.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.xdrradiology.com/core/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/product-banner-software.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Fast, Easy And More Diagnostic For One Study</h2>
<p>Actual scan time is approximately 20 seconds for full mouth. Panoramic images provide more coverage for bone defects and jaw lesions.</p>
<h2>All Members Of Your Staff Fully Confident Using The Tools So They Can Focus Their Attention On Patients Not Devices</h2>
<ul>
<li>You can be confident that your support team is diligent and knowledgeable to assist you in succeeding</li>
</ul>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.dmiequipment.ie/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/DIS_All_images_LoRes.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dental Imaging Software" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Access to a wealth of new diagnostic information</h2>
<ul>
<li>Your staff should feel confident in using these tools, so that they can concentrate on the patients and not the devices.</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
